Joshua Ludwig

213 Bainbridge St, Philadelphia, PA 484-429-1584 <u>ihludwig94@gmail.com</u>

OBJECTIVE

Analytical decision-maker with 2 years experience driving growth in a gritty early-stage start-up, seeking an opportunity where my adaptable thinking and determination will create value for both my organization and its users/clients. I am focused on roles within disruptive technology companies where I can continue to groom and expand my project management and general management talents alongside enthusiastic and ambitious colleagues.

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATIONS

University of Delaware

Bachelor of Science in Management Information Systems

May 2017

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

Statistics With R, Introduction to Probability and Data (Through Duke University) MISY 430/431: Applied Project Management

- Developed a form submission web app for the Department of Hospitality at the University of Delaware to log student service hours using agile methodology, which improved data reporting/retention processes.
- Informed client with project management tools (Wireframes, Gantt Chart, Process Flows, User Stories).

WORK EXPERIENCE

VeryApt

Operations Manager

January 2018-Current

- Created listing agreements with multiple large-scale residential rental companies to add \$25,000+ in annual revenues
- Acted as the procuring agent in 100+ residential leases, maintaining a conversion rate above the targeted 10% of users that enter our system (roughly \$100,000 in revenue annually).
- Led weekly team meetings, identifying individual and team performance objectives, then defining and troubleshooting any business problems that impeded progress towards those benchmarks.
- Managed Drexel Co-op students for summer internships, guiding their productivity goals, personal development objectives, organizational on-boarding etc.
- Reported to shareholders and executive management on traffic, profitability, growth, etc.
- Created hand-off documentation to solidify business processes that previously lacked material recording.

Hardwick Benfer LLC

Data Analyst

August 2017-December 2017

- Took source data (10,000+ records) provided by a Fortune 100 company in legal discovery and modeled using Excel (macros, vlookups with multiple criteria, pivot tables) to build a quantitative prosecution.
- Built and presented data visualizations to defense teams resulting in multiple pre-trial settlements.

John I. Weinberg Center for Corporate Governance

Corporate Governance Intern & Teaching Assistant, Professor Charles Elson

February 2015-May 2017

- Teaching Assistant for Professor Charles Elson's "Advanced Seminar in Corporate Governance" -consulted students on term papers, designed and led review sessions, and graded examinations/papers.
- Led planning and execution of bi-annual Governance Symposiums (budgeting, logistics, venue reservation).

ACTIVITIES

Philabundance

Volunteer

January 2019-Current

 Accumulated 20 volunteer hours packing and organizing Hunger Relief Center boxes, with an estimated impact value of \$500 since starting.

The Review (University of Delaware Student Newspaper)

Writer

Fall 2014-Spring 2015

- Met weekly deadlines to accommodate the editing and publishing process.
- Published multiple stories backed by extensive first-hand research.

Phi Kappa Psi Fraternity

Philanthropy Chair

Winter 2014-Fall 2016

- Designed philanthropy events (Introduced 2 annual events) that continue to raise money today.
- Maintained relationships with Boys & Girls Club of Newark and routinely handled donations of event profits to various subsidiary groups.